A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
عقرب دقائق مسرِع، مُذنّب ساقط
Conan's logic works wonders on hearts tired by modern society!
تُعالج استنتاجات كونان القلوب المُثقلة بالمجتمع الحديث
Today's finally the last chapter!
!اليوم هو جزء الحلّ أخيراً
An unexpected culprit beneath the mask!
!مجرم غير متوقّع تحت القناع
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
Ran, the old man, and I attended the Izu Mystery Tour
ذهبتُ مع ران والعمّ في جولة غموض إيزو
in place of Professor Agasa, his friend, and his friend's granddaughter.
مكان البروفسور آغاسا وصديقه وحفيدته الذين لم يستطيعوا الحضور
Whoever determines the organizer's identity gets to stay for free
الهدف من هذه الجولة هو إيجاد المُنظّم الذي يختبئ بين المشاركين
and receives floppy disks containing a certain program.
ومن يفعل، يحصل على أقراص مرنة تحوي برنامجاً ما
But then Ebara-san-- dressed as the Night Baron-- fell to his death!
لكنّ إيبارا-سان الذي كان يرتدي زيّ بارون الليل سقط على المطعم المفتوح ولقي حتفه
It was clearly a murder!
!كانت جريمة قتل بكلّ وضوح
How did the killer leave after pushing Ebara-san off his veranda?
كيف غادر القاتل بعد دفعه إيبارا-سان من الشرفة؟
He then knocked out a karate expert guarding the body
ثمّ أفقد الشرطيّ حارس الجثّة وعيه مع أنّه خبير في الكاراتيه
and appeared before us as the Night Baron!
!وظهر أمامنا بزيّ بارون الليل
Ran's kicks were useless.
لم تنفع ركلات ران
Could the killer be--
...أيمكن أنّ القاتل
The Night Baron Murder Case (The Solution)
(جريمة قتل بارون الليل (جزء الحلّ
Was that policeman really a karate expert?!
أكان ما قلتماه حقيقياً؟ أنّ الشرطي الذي فقد وعيه خبيراً في الكاراتيه؟
Yeah, third-level black belt.
أجل، يمتلك حزام المستوى الثالث الأسود
For reals?!
!صدقاً؟
Who could've done that?
كيف هُزم شخص مثله؟
Come to think of it, he did dodge all of Ran's kicks!
!بالمناسبة، لم تصبه أيّ ركلات ران
The only suspect capable of reading her attacks is...
الوحيد بين المشتبه بهم الذي ...يمتلك القدرة على التنبّؤ بحركاتها
...the karate champ, Maeda Satoru!
!هو بطل الكاراتيه الوطنيّ السابق، مايدا ساتورو
So that's why neither of them ran after the Night Baron!
لذا لم تلحق ران أو أكيكو-سان ببارون الليل آنذاك
They had both realized it was him!
!أدركتا أنّه كان مايدا-سان
Ran...
...ران
What would Shinichi do in this situation?
...ما قد يفعل شينتشي في هذا الوضع؟ شينتشي
If I knew the culprit?
ماذا؟ إذا كنتُ أعرف القاتل؟
Yeah. Like what if it was Professor Agasa?
أجل، لو كان المجرم البروفسور آغاسا مثلاً
I'd turn him in.
سأقولها
You would?!
ماذا؟ حقّاً؟
Yeah. I'd flat out say, "You did it!"
أجل، سأصرّح بوضوح أنّه الفاعل
So you can look cool, huh?
كي تبدو رائعاً إذاً؟
Nope.
لن يكون هناك مكان للروعة
I'd probably be dead tired by then...
فسأكون بحالٍ يُرثى لها آنذاك
I'd have tried my utmost to prove that they didn't do it first...
من إعياء البحث عن أعذار وتبريرات قد تبرئ ساحته
Alright!
!حسناً
Sorry, Satoru. If only I hadn't recommended this tour...
آسفة يا ساتورو، لو لم أقترح أن نشارك ...في هذه الجولة
It's okay. I came along because I wanted to.
لا بأس، فقد أردتُ القدوم
This is all the Night Baron's fault...
كلّها غلطة بارون الليل
Satoru. Don't tell me you--
...ساتورو، أيمكن أنّك
No, it's nothing!
كلا، لا شيء
I'm going to bed. Good night.
سأخلد للنوم، عُمت مساءً
Good night.
عُمتِ مساءً
Interrogation Room
غرفة استجواب للأشخاص المعنيّين فقط
Detective Yokomizo.
محقق يوكوميزو
We have a lost item from the victim's room.
أحضرنا غرضاً مفقوداً من غرفة الضحيّة
You do?
حقّاً؟
There's something odd on the security lock.
يوجد شيء غريب على قفل الأمان
What?
ما هو؟
Let me see.
دعني أرى
Yes. This is cellophane tape.
أجل، هذا شريط لاصق شفّاف
Huh?
ماذا؟
Conan-kun!
كونان-كن
Alright, who set the security lock?!
!من ربط قفل الأمان؟
I locked it from the outside!
ربطتُه من الخارج
Using this cellophane tape!
باستعمال هذا الشريط اللاصق الشفّاف
First, you cut yourself an appropriate length
تقطعه بطول مناسب أوّلاً
and then fold it in two, leaving a few centimeters of the sticky part.
ثمّ تطويه وتترك بضعة سنتيمترات في الجانب اللاصق
Then you align the lock perpendicularly, place the tape on it,
بعدها تضع القفل عامودياً بالنسبة للحائط وتمدّ الشريط اللاصق عليه
and close the door.
وتغلق الباب
One tug of the tape and--
...بسحبك للشريط من الخارج
It locked!
!قُفل
Pull it more, and... the tape comes off and the evidence disappears.
تسحبه أكثر... ويُنزع الشريط فيزول الدليل
See?
رأيتم؟
I dunno... Don't these rooms have auto-locks?
لكن هل سينجح هذا من المرة الأولى؟ فغرف هذه الفندق آليّة القفل
That's okay!
لا بأس
You can use a room key to see if a room is locked or not,
يمكنك التحقق من نجاح الإقفال من عدمه إذا كان معك مفتاح الغرفة
and you can peel the tape off if need be!
وحتّى إن قُطع الشريط اللاصق، يمكنك نزعه
But this tip would've been in the killer's blind spot!
كما هذا الطرف خارج مجال نظر الفاعل
So he must not have noticed this tape left behind!
!لذا لم ينتبه لتبقّي أثر للشريط
Say, wasn't the key lying with his clothes near the door?
بالمناسبة، ألم يكن المفتاح على الأرض بجوار الباب مع الثياب؟
Oh, yeah! That's right!
!صحيح، فهمت
After the killer took his key, dressed him up, and threw him over,
بعدما أخذ الفاعل المفتاح من الضحيّة وألبسه زيّ بارون الليل وأسقطه
he left the room and set the security lock using this trick!
غادر الغرفة واستعمل الحيلة آنفة الذكر لقفل الباب
Then, after double-checking the lock, he tossed the key into the room!
وبعد تحققه من القفل، رمى المفتاح داخل الغرفة من فجوة الباب وهرب
That would seal the room and make it look like an accident!
!هكذا تكون الغرفة مقفلة، ويمكن جعله يبدو حادثاً
How'd you figure out that trick?
كيف اكتشفت هذه الحيلة؟
I saw it on a mystery show.
رأيتها في مسلسل غموض على التلفاز
So the issue now is in the alibis of our six suspects!
المشكلة المتبقية الآن هي حجج غياب المُشتبه بهم الستّة
Maeda-san, who was with Ran and Conan...
...مايدا-سان الذي قال أنّه كان مع ران-سان وكونان
Sayama-san, who was watching TV...
وساياما-سان التي قالت أنّها كانت تشاهد التلفاز في غرفتها
Konno-san, who was in his room reading his e-mail...
وكونّو-سان الذي قال أنّه كان يقرأ بريده الإلكتروني في غرفته كذلك
Kamijo-san, who was in the pub with Mori-san...
وكاميجو-سان التي كانت في الحانة مع موري-سان
And Kaneshiro-san and Hayashi-san, who were in the outside restaurant.
وكانيشيرو-سان وهاياشي-سان اللذان كانا في المطعم المفتوح
I know Sayama-san's alibi.
أعرف حجّة غياب ساياما-سان
She said she called the front desk at 10:00.
قالت أنّها اتّصلت بمكتب الاستقبال عند العاشرة
Yes, she did ask for a wake-up call at 10:00.
أجل، طلبت اتّصال إيقاظ صباحي عند العاشرة بالفعل
I remember her call well. It was right after I heard people screaming.
أذكر اتّصالها، فقد كان بعدما سمعت صراخ الناس
The victim was in Room 2101. She couldn't have done it...
كان الضحيّة في الغرفة 2101، ربما لم يكن ...بمقدورها ارتكاب الجريمة
Plus she was with Ran and Conan when they ran into the Night Baron.
كانت أكيكو-سان مع ران وكونان عندما التقيا بارون الليل أيضاً
She's in the clear.
فهي بريئة
But why did the killer do that? Or even steal the costume?
لكن لمَ فعل القاتل ذلك؟ سرق زيّ بارون الليل حتّى
They were probably worried when we realized it was a murder!
لا بدّ أنّه كان قلقاً بعدما اكتشفنا أنّها كانت جريمة قتل
That's gotta be it!
!لا شكّ بذلك
Do you have records of Konno-san in Room 2002?
ألديكم سجّلات لكونّو-سان في الغرفة 2002؟
He supposedly used the phone for online access until after 10:00.
يُفترض أنّه استعمل خطّ الهاتف لدخول الإنترنت حتّى بعد العاشرة بقليل
Yes. He used it from 9:45 until 10:06.
أجل، استعمله من 9:45 حتّى 10:06
But that doesn't mean he spoke with anyone!
لكن لا يعني ذلك أنّه كان يكلّم أحدهم
Sounds suspicious to me...
يبدو مريباً لي
Kamijo-san is suspicious too.
كاميجو-سان التي كانت في الحانة معك تبدو مريبة أيضاً
Darn him!
...هـ-هذا الوغد
Princess Hotel 2F Pub Emerald
الطابق الثاني لفندق الأميرة (حانة (الزمّرد
She put pills in my drink?!
!وضعت كاميجو-سان حبوباً في كأسي؟
Yes. You fell asleep afterward...
أجل، غلبك النوم بعدها
I knew it! Those were sleeping pills she had!
كنتُ أعرف! تلك الحبوب بحوزتها حبوب منوّمة
Did she drug him to create an alibi?
هل دسّتها في شراب العمّ لصنع حجّة غياب؟
What about her?
ماذا فعلت بعدها؟
She went to the restroom, but returned five minutes later.
ذهبت لدورة المياه، لكنّها رجعت بعد 5 دقائق
So she was here when the murder occurred?
كانت هنا عندما وقعت الحادثة إذاً؟
Yes. She left when she heard the commotion.
أجل، غادرت بعدما سمعت الجلبة
Were those old folks really here?
أكان العجوز وخادمته هنا حقّاً؟
Yes. They rushed to the front of the crowd after hearing someone fell.
أجل، هرعا لمقدمة الحشد بعدما سمعا بسقوط أحد
The front?
المقدمة؟
Darn! I suspected them!
!تبّاً! اشتبهتُ بهما
It's okay. We've narrowed it down to two suspects now!
لا مشكلة، قلّصنا المشتبه بهم لاثنين الآن
That's true.
هذا صحيح
The only ones with unconfirmed alibis
الوحيدان دون حجّة غياب مؤكدة
are Konno-san and Maeda-san.
هما كونّو-سان ومايدا-سان فحسب
Maeda-san was with us in the observation lounge,
كان مايدا-سان معنا في صالة المراقبة
but he's the one who checked the time, so he could've lied.
،لكنّه كان الوحيد الذي تفقّد الوقت فكان بإمكانه تزييفه
And considering that the knocked-out officer was a karate expert,
كما بوضع الشرطيّ في الاعتبار الذي ...كان خبير كاراتيه وأفقده الفاعل وعيه
Maeda-san must be the one who--
...لا يتبين سوى أنّ الفاعل مايدا-سان
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Ran-neechan!
...ران-نيتشان
Where's Dad?
أ-أين أبي؟
Over there. What happened?
هناك، ما الخطب؟
I found an alibi for Maeda-san!
!وجدتُ حجّة غياب لمايدا-سان
After he left us, he met some fans at the lounge entrance!
بعدما انفصل عنّا، التقى بمعجبتين له !عند مدخل الصالة
They even asked for the date and time with his autographs!
!طلبتا منه توقيعه مع تدوين الوقت والتاريخ
The time was 10:03!
كان الوقت 10:03
They're sure of it, because they even checked their own watches!
!إنّهما متأكدتان بما أنّهما نظرا لساعتيهما
Shouldn't you bring them here, then?
ألا يجدر بنا استدعاؤهما إذاً؟
Right! I'll go get them!
!معك حقّ، سأجلبهما سريعاً
Ah! So Maeda-san wasn't the killer!
هكذا إذاً، لم يكن مايدا-سان الفاعل
Wait a minute!
...لحظة
Then why didn't he mention it when he was questioned?!
لمَ لم يذكر أمرهما عند استجوابه إذاً؟
It's an airtight alibi!
إنّها حجّة غياب مُحكمة
Maybe he couldn't mention it?
ربما لم يستطع؟
But why?
لمَ؟
It's the pen I dropped. It's leaking ink from the shock...
إنّه القلم الذي أوقعتُه! الحبر يسيل من صدمة السقوط
Not surprising; it did fall from Ebara-san's room on the 21st floor...
لا عجب، فقد سقط من غرفة إيبارا-سان في الطابق 21
Huh?
...ماذا
That's odd. He fell off the same veranda but hit the statue...
هذا غريب، سقط إيبارا-سان من نفس الشرفة لكنّه وقع على التمثال
I know! The wind blew it over...
...فهمت، جرفتُه الرياح
The wind?!
الرياح؟
Hey, waitress lady!
!أيّتها النادلة
Yes?
ماذا؟
Was the wind blowing when that person fell?
أكانت الرياح تهبّ عندما سقط ذاك الشخص؟
Come to think of it, there was a strong wind...
بالتفكير في الأمر، كانت هناك ريح قويّة
It constantly blows at night this time of the year.
تهبّ باستمرار ليلاً في هذا الوقت من العام
From the left of that statue to the right.
من يسار هذا التمثال ليمينه
It's our famous 'Princess Wind'!
تُدعى بريح الأميرة، ومن سمات هذا المكان المعروفة
It's a lot stronger higher up, though!
رغم أنّ الريح في الأعلى أقوى
Hold on a second!
...لحظة
There's one place where the wind is--
...كان هناك مكان واحد حيث الريح
No question about it! That person is the killer!
!لا شكّ، القاتل هو ذاك الشخص
What?! The knocked-out officer was a karate expert?!
ماذا؟! الشرطيّ الذي أُفقد وعيه !كان خبير كاراتيه؟
Okay! Now I know who did it!
!حسناً! عرفت الفاعل
I will now begin my explanation! Gather all the suspects here!
!سأبدأ شرح استنتاجاتي الآن! اجمعوا كلّ المشتبه بهم هنا
Right!
!حاضر
Not good...
!هذا سيّئ
Officers!
!حضرة الضبّاط
The detective wants you to do this stuff in the suspects' rooms.
يريد عمّي المتحرّي أن تنفذوا المكتوب هنا في غرف المشتبه بهم
What is this?
ما هذا؟
Says it's an experiment!
يقول أنّها تجربة
And that it'll prove who did it!
وستكشف هويّة الفاعل
Concerning your alibis for when the victim fell at 10:00...
حسناً، بخصوص حجج غيابكم وقت سقوط الضحيّة عند العاشرة
The alibis of Kaneshiro-san, Hayashi-san, Sayama-san, and Kamijo-san
تمّ التحقق من حجج غياب كانيشيرو-سان وهاياشي-سان وساياما-سان وكاميجو-سان، هؤلاء الأربعة
Darn it! Where's the signal?!
تبّاً! لم تظهر الإشارة بعد؟
The only ones with vague alibis
اللذان بحجّة غياب ضعيفة
are Maeda-san, who was in the observation lounge,
هما مايدا-سان الذي كان في صالة المراقبة
and Konno-san, who was in his room,
وكونّو-سان الذي كان في غرفته
but after murdering the victim, the killer stupidly stole the costume
لكن تصرّف القاتل بطيش بعد ارتكابه الجريمة وسرق زيّ بارون الليل
from the office where the body was
من الغرفة التي كانت فيها الجثّة
and then ran into Sayama-san and the others...
ثمّ مرّ بجماعة ساياما-سان
...unaware that the officer he knocked out was a karate expert!
لم يكن في علمه أنّ الشرطي الذي أفقده وعيه كان خبيراً في الكاراتيه
A karate expert?!
خبير في الكاراتيه؟
Yes.
أجل
The only one capable of knocking such a person out in one blow...
الوحيد القادر على إفقاد شخص كهذا ...وعيه بضربة واحدة
...is the former Japanese karate champion, Maeda Satoru-san--
هو بطل الكاراتيه الوطنيّ السابق، مايدا ساتورو-سان
Wait, Dad!
!انتظر يا أبي
Maeda-san didn't do it!
!لم يكن مايدا-سان الفاعل
He was with them when it happened!
فقد كان معهما وقت وقوع الجريمة
It's true!
!إنّها الحقيقة
No way!
...لا يمكن
Then who did it?
من كان الفاعل إذاً؟
Will you get serious?!
هلّا وضّحت الأمر؟
That's it!
!فهمت
The killer is the alibi-less Konno Shiro!
!القاتل هو عديم حجّة الغياب، أنت يا كونّو شيرو
Don't be fooled by his looks, everyone!
!لا يخدعكم مظهره جميعاً
Hide it as he may, this man is actually a karate expert!
قد يخفي الأمر، لكنّ هذا الرجل !خبير كاراتيه في الواقع
Or not...
...لا يمكن ذلك
Quit fooling around!
!كفّ عن العبث
There it is! The signal!
!ها هي! الإشارة
Who's the killer?!
!من القاتل؟
Mori-san! Can you tell us already?
موري-سان! هلّا أخبرتنا مباشرةً؟
Are you really a skilled detective?!
أأنت مُتحرٍّ عظيم حقّاً؟
Like I said, the killer is--
...كما أخبرتكم، القاتل
Mori-san!
!موري-سان
Well, enough of this foolishness.
لننه الهزل هنا
Will you ever get serious?!
...أنت
Hold on. This is the pose he takes when he starts analyzing.
تمهلي، هذه وضعية موري-سان الفريدة عندما يبدأ شرح استنتاجاته
Right, Ran-san?
أليس كذلك يا ران-سان؟
Yes!
!بلى
Before I begin, please step away from the statue and out of harm's way.
قبل بدء تحليلي، أرجو أن تبتعدوا عن التمثال وتتجنبوا الخطر
What are you going to do?
ما الذي ستُقدم عليه؟
An experiment.
تجربة
What are these?!
ما-ما هذه؟
Blankets that I had dressed up as people and dropped from above.
ألحِفة أمرتُ بجعلها تبدو كالبشر وإسقاطها من الأعلى
Dropped from each of the suspects' rooms, with their numbers on them.
من كلّ غرف المشتبه بهم، وبأرقامها عليها
Room 2101!
!غرفة 2101
This is from Ebara Tokio-san's room, where the murder occurred!
هذه غرفة الضحيّة إيبارا توكيو-سان !حيث وقعت الجريمة
But he fell directly onto that statue!
لكنّه سقط على التمثال مباشرة
It couldn't have been carried this far by the wind.
مهما كان للرياح تأثير، يستحيل أن يسقط ...بعيداً لهذا الحد
But it was. By the 'Princess Wind'.
كان تأثير الرياح، المعروفة برياح الأميرة
This strong wind blows past the
...تهبّ ريح قويّة
hotel at nights this time of year...
ليلاً على الفندق في هذا الموسم
From the left of
من يسار التمثال
the statue to the right.
إلى يمينه
It was also blowing when the victim fell. Correct, Miss?
كانت تهبّ وقت سقوط الضحيّة إيبارا-سان أيضاً، صحيح أيّتها النادلة؟
Yes! I think it was blowing even harder than it is now!
أ-أجل! أظنّها كانت تهبّ أقوى من الآن حينذاك
Moreover, he was wearing an outfit with high air resistance.
كما كان يرتدي الضحيّة زيّ بارون الليل الذي يسهل على الرياح حمله
If he had been pushed off his own veranda,
،لو أُلقي الضحيّة من شرفة غرفته
I doubt he would've fallen onto the statue directly below.
فيصعب تصديق أنّه سيسقط على التمثال أسفلها تماماً
Even the blanket dropped from Kaneshiro-san's room one floor below
حتّى اللحاف المُلقى من غرفة كانيشيرو-سان التي تدنوها بطابق
is lying far off to the side.
على الأرض بجوارها
Now I see!
!فهمت
We were fooled by the glove on the veranda and the locked room trick!
خدعنا القفّاز الذي كان عالقاً !بسوار الشرفة وحيلة الغرفة المقفلة
Those weren't meant to simply make it look like an accident--
...لم تكن حيلةً لجعلها تبدو حادثة فحسب
they were also traps to make it look like that's where it happened!
!بلّ فخّاً لتزييف مكان وقوع الجريمة
Correct. The killer didn't lock the room after the murder;
أجل، لم يقفل القاتل الغرفة بعد ارتكاب الجريمة
he locked it before committing the murder in his own room!
!أقفلها قبل ارتكاب الجريمة في غرفته الخاصة
Meaning the most suspect are... the blankets lying by the statue!
...ما يعني أنّ الأكثر شبهة !هي الألحِفة بجوار التمثال
Room 2102's Kamijo-san, Room 2002's Konno-san, and--
...غرفة 2102 لكاميجو-سان، وغرفة 2002 لكونّو-سان
--Room 1901's Sayama-san!
!غرفة 1901 لساياما-سان
It's just coincidence! After all, everyone else's are by the statue, too!
كانت مصادفة! فألحفة البقيّة حول التمثال أيضاً
It's indeed a coincidence that it was pierced,
اختراق التمثال للحاف كان صدفة بالفعل
but it's no coincidence that it fell there!
!لكن موضع سقوطه ليس صدفة
Besides, the killer is neither Kamijo-san nor Konno-san!
كما أنّ القاتل ليس كاميجو-سان ولا كونّو-سان
Their windows are off to the side of the victim's veranda.
فنافذتَي غرفتيهما على الجانب الآخر من شرفة الضحيّة
Looking at the point of impact, it would be instantly obvious
بالنظر لمكان السقوط، يتّضح فورياً أنّ الضحيّة
that he didn't fall from there.
لم يسقط من هناك
But Sayama-san's room is directly below theirs!
لكنّ غرفة ساياما-سان أسفلهما تماماً
Her room's blanket must've just happened to land there--
...لعلّ لحاف غرفتها سقط هناك بالمصادفة
It didn't just 'happen to.'
لم تكن مصادفة
There's a spot...
يوجد موضع واحد
One directly below the victim's veranda where there's almost no wind!
أسفل شرفة غرفة الضحيّة حيث تكاد لا تكون هناك رياح
The call she made to the front desk to create an alibi
اتّصالها بمكتب الاستقبال لصنع حجّة غياب
conversely proves that she was in the room at the time of the murder.
ينقلب ليثبت أنّها كانت في غرفتها وقت وقوع الجريمة
So then the killer is--
...القاتل إذاً
No! I did it! I pushed him off!
!كـ-كلا! أنا القاتل! أنا من دفع ذاك الرجل
She has nothing to do with it! She even ran into the killer...
!لا علاقة لأكيكو! ودليل ذلك أنّها واجهت القاتل
...me, dressed as the Night Baron!
!أنا بزيّ بارون الليل
Yes, it was me! I did it all alone--
...أجل، كان أنا! كلّه من فعلي
Satoru.
ساتورو
So it was you who did that to cover for me...
كان أنت من قام بذلك ...للتغطية عليّ إذاً
Cover for you?!
للتغطية عليك؟
Indeed.
أجل
Maeda-san stole the Night Baron costume and ran into her
سرق مايدا-سان زيّ بارون الليل وظهر أمامها
to rid her of all suspicion.
لتبرئتها من الشبهة
But he was not an accomplice.
لكنّه لم يكن مُعاوناً في الجريمة
He did it of his own accord when he realized who the killer was.
فعل ذلك من تلقاء نفسه بعدما أدرك حقيقة الجريمة وفاعلها
Yes. Upon seeing the necktie's knot, for example.
أجل، بعد رؤيته لعقدة ربط العنق على سبيل المثال
It's unclear if that was the killer's own style or not,
ليس واضحاً ما إن كان أسلوب القاتل الخاص أم لا
but Maeda-san did find something in his room.
لكنّ مايدا-سان وجد شيئاً في غرفته
Something that was floating in the pool later...
شيء كان يطفو في المسبح لاحقاً
The wig!
!الشعر المستعار
Yes.
أجل
He was likely convinced when he found it among the killer's things...
تيقّن بعدما وجده ضمن أمتعة القاتل غالباً
Convinced that she was the killer!
!تيقّن أنّها الفاعلة
That can't be!
لا-لا يمكن
The wig was in the room because Ebara-san and the Night Baron
كان الشعر المستعار في الغرفة لأنّ إيبارا-سان وبارون الليل
happened to have the same hairstyle, making it unnecessary!
صادف أنّهما بنفس قصّة الشعر، فلم تعد بحاجته
So that's why he risked running into her
...فهمت! لذا خاطر بسرقة الرداء
with the stolen costume and the wig on!
!والشعر المستعار وظهر أمامها
Yes. And he was prepared to be caught.
نعم، كان متحضّراً لأن يُقبض عليه
The reason he kept quiet about having people to vouch for his alibi
سبب إخفائه لوجود شهود على حجّة غيابه
was because it would cause problems if he were caught.
هو لأنّ ذلك سيعيق خطّته إذا ما تمّ القبض عليه
He planned to take the fall in place of Akiko-san if it came down to it!
نوى أن يكون كبش فداء ويأخذ التهمة مكان أكيكو-سان إذا تطلّب الأمر
Don't make me laugh.
لا تُضحكني
Thanks to you, my perfect crime was ruined!
!أفسدت جريمتي الكاملة بسببك
Akiko!
...أ-أكيكو
That's right, I did it! I killed him!
!صحيح، كنتُ أنا! أنا من قتله
To avenge my brother who he murdered three years ago!
!للانتقام لأخي الذي قتله قبل 3 أعوام
Murdered?!
!قُتل؟
Pretty much!
بمثابة القتل
He hacked the 'Workshop' software my brother bet the company on!
فقد اخترق برنامج "الورشة" الذي !كان عماد شركة أخي
Workshop?!
!الورشة؟
You know about it?!
أتعرفينه؟
Yes, it's the software Ebara sold me three years ago!
أجل، إنّه البرنامج الذي باعه لي إيبارا لي قبل ثلاثة أعوام
Had I known it was stolen, I would've taken it off the market!
!لكنّي أوقفت بيعه فورما اكتشفتُ أنّه مسروق
My brother jumped off the company building before that!
!قفز أخي من سطح مبنى شركته قبل ذلك
I've lived to avenge him ever since...
...عشتُ للأخذ بثأره مُذ ذاك اليوم
...and then I came up with this Mystery Tour.
وخططتُ لجولة الغموض هذه
My lure was the infamous 'Night Baron' virus.
طُعم استدراج إيبارا كان فيروس بارون الليل الذي ذاع صيتاً في السابق
He immediately took the bait... unaware that it didn't exist...
أكل الطُعم فوراً... دون علمه أن البرنامج ليس موجوداً
Yes. After I drove Satoru off, the bait I used to lure Ebara
...أجل، بعدما طردتُ ساتورو من الغرفة
He rushed over immediately,
أتى فوراً
once he got a whiff of the virus's location.
بعدما أعطيتُه تلميحات عن مكان الفيروس
Then I put sleeping pills in his drink, locked his room as planned,
،وضعتُ حبوب منوّمة في شرابه وأقفلت غرفته وفق الخطّة
then sent him plummeting from my room!
ثم ألقيته لحتفه من غرفتي
Just like my brother!
!كما لقي أخي حتفه
My only oversight was that you, Mori Kogoro, would be on the tour!
غفلتي الوحيدة كانت عدم إدراك مشاركتك في هذه الجولة يا موري كوغورو
But you didn't even blink after I pushed Conan-kun into the pool.
دفعتُ كونان-كن ليسقط في المسبح لأخيفك، لكنّك لم تتزحزح البتّة
Satoru. This is the kind of woman I am.
ساتورو، أنا امرأة من هذا النوع
So hurry and forget about me!
لذا يجدر بك نسياني سريعاً
I'll be waiting.
سأنتظرك
I'll be waiting until you get out!
سأبقى منتظراً حتّى ترجعي
You dummy...
...أحمق
After that, Akiko-san slightly nodded and got into the police car.
بعدها، انحنت أكيكو-سان بخفّة بينما صعدت سيّارة الشرطة
Maeda-san was taken into another car for police obstruction,
ونُقل مايدا-سان بسيّارة أخرى لإعاقته للتحقيق
but Detective Yokomizo says he may get off on mitigating circumstances.
لكن وفقاً للمُحقق يوكوميزو، سيُرفق في الحكم عليه بظروف مُخفّفة
As we watched the cars leave,
،أثناء مراقبتنا لمغادرة سيّارتهما بصمت
only the Princess Wind cried sadly around us.
كان نحيب رياح الأميرة الحزين هو الصوت الوحيد المسموع
So that's why you drugged his drink...
لذا وضعتِ حبوب منوّمة في شرابه؟
That's right.
أجل
I figured I could check his notes to find out who the Night Baron was.
ظننتُ أنّي سأكتشف هويّة بارون الليل إذا تفقّدتُ دفتر ملاحظاته
But his notebook was blank.
لكنّه لم يكتب فيه شيء
Why would you go that far?
لمَ قد تفعلين كلّ ذلك؟
I only wanted the virus so I could make a vaccine.
أردتُ الفيروس كي أصنع لقاحاً لا أكثر
It looks like they wanted it for bad reasons, though.
لكن يبدو أنّ النوايا الشريرة كانت تتأجج داخل هؤلاء
How uncouth.
!هذه مبالغة
I simply wished to punish the owner of the virus
أردتُ معاقبة مالك الفيروس فحسب
that ruined my beloved software 'son' four years ago!
الشخص الذي دمّر برنامجي الأشبه بابني !الذي صنعته قبل أربعة أعوام
And you even faked your bad eyesight?
تظاهرت بعماك حتّى؟
Oh, you knew?
عجباً، لاحظتَ إذاً؟
I had hoped to keep people off guard...
فعلتُ ذلك كيلا يأخذ الآخرون حيطتهم حولي
What kind of software was it?
ما كان برنامجك بالضبط؟
I believe it was--
...حسناً، أظنّه
--'Project: High School Girl Paradise', sir.
مشروع جنّة فتيات المدارس الثانوية" يا سيّدي"
That reminds me, I heard you scoured the entire hotel
بالمناسبة، سمعت يا ران-تشان أنّك قلبتِ الفندق رأساً على عقب
to prove Maeda-san's alibi!
في بحثك عن حجّة غياب لمايدا-سان
I really looked up to him!
!كان قدوةً أتطلّع لها
Plus 'he' taught me that you can't ever give up...
...كما هنالك شخص علّمني بألّا أستسلم حتّى النهاية
'He'?
شخص؟
Oh? You called your boyfriend?
ماذا؟ هل اتّصلتِ بحبيبك؟
No, that's not what I mean!
!كلا، لم أقصد ذلك
Who is 'he'?!
!من ذاك الشخص؟
Not you too, Conan-kun!
!حتّى أنت يا كونان-كن
You know who! That wandering mystery geek!
أقصد مهووس التحرّي ذاك الذي !يتجوّل في مكان ما الآن غالباً
Come on! Hang in there!
!ما الخطب؟! تماسك
Hey, look!
!يا عمّ
Guts-Man!
!غاتس مان
Hey! Did you drink that?!
!هل شربت منها؟
Say, there's a seal on that Guts-Man!
يوجد ختم على قنّينة غاتس مان هذه
It's for a special campaign, but it ended three days ago!
إنّه لحملة هدايا خاصة، لكنّها انتهت قبل ثلاثة أيام
As proof, there aren't any on your bottles.
ودليلاً على ذلك، الختم ليس موجوداً على قنّينتي العم
No, there aren't.
معك حق
The Stalker Murder Case
جريمة قتل المُلاحق
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Glue.
صمغ
Next episode's case is socially relevant.
!قضيّة الحلقة القادمة اجتماعية
And there's a new ending.
!ستكون هناك شارة نهاية جديدة